Almas Baimagambetov

STATEMENT

I am a Lecturer in Game Development at the University of Brighton, where I teach a range of computer science, software and game development modules. My research is in the field of data visualization. I am the author and maintainer of FXGL, a game engine used by several academic institutions to teach game development. I contribute to numerous projects on GitHub and run an educational YouTube channel covering game and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept. 2018 - Present	$ \begin{array}{c} \text{Lecturer in Game Development} \\ \textit{University of Brighton, UK} \end{array} $
Oct. 2017 - Aug. 2018	Part-time Lecturer in Game Development $University \ of \ Brighton, \ UK$
Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017	Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Game Development $University\ of\ Brighton,\ UK$
Jan 2013 - Oct. 2016	In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan
Oct. 2012 - Feb. 2015	Guest Speaker and Mentor for IT students (Volunteer) Bellerbys College, UK

EDUCATION

Feb. 2019 - July 2020 (Expected)	PGCert in LT HE, University of Brighton, UK
July 2015 - April 2020 (Expected)	PhD in Computer Science, University of Brighton, UK Thesis: automated visualization of grouped networks using Euler diagrams and graphs keywords: set theory, graph theory, topology, computational geometry & graphics
Oct.2012 - July 2015	BSc Computer Science (Games), University of Brighton, UK Final year project: analysis of software development issues in large scale games Project grade: 87% (A+), Degree: 1st Class Honours

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced: Java, JavaFX, Kotlin,

game engine development (ECS, AI, UI, IO, serialization, physics,

event systems, networking, scripting),

API design, TDD, FDD, DDD, CI, deployment, software development principles and practices,

algorithms and data structures

Intermediate: C++, JS, SDL2, OpenGL, Git, Win/Mac/Linux, Agile, LATEX Beginner: Unity, SQL, HTML, CSS, Haskell, Python, Node.js, Spring

Interests and Activities

game development, software development, computer science, education, technology data visualization, automated graphical layout generation, open-source, chess

AWARDS

June 2018	Best Student Paper, Diagrams 2018 Conference
Sept. 2015	International Research Scholarship (50% fee reduction)
	University of Brighton
July 2015	Best Final Year Development Project (£250)
	The FDM Group Prize
Nov. 2014	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000)
	University of Brighton
Nov. 2013	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000)
	University of Brighton
June 2012	Top #1 Foundation Student, Bellerbys College
May 2012	Best IT Student, Bellerbys College
RESEARCH	H AND PROFESSIONAL TALKS
April 2020	The State-of-the-art in Java Cross-platform Development
-	(Brighton Java Meetup)
March 2020	Effective Grouped Networks
	(CEM Research Seminar)
June 2019	Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks Using Euler Diagrams and Graphs
	(CEM Conference)
April 2019	Java and JavaFX Game Development
	(Brighton Java Meetup)
June 2018	Generating Effective Euler Diagrams
	(10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams)
May 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation
	(University of Brighton Internal Conference)
March 2017	Data Visualization Workshop
	(Presenter at Data Visualization Brighton Meetup)
Feb. 2017	An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation
	(Visual Modelling Group Talk)
June 2016	Grouped Networks and Associated Challenges
3.5	(University of Brighton Internal Conference)
May 2016	Euler Diagram Generation Techniques
	(Visual Modelling Group Talk)

Publications

- 1. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Stapleton, G., Howse, J. and Blake, A. (2020) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 11th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Tallinn, 24-28 August 2020. (submitted for long paper).
- 2. **Baimagambetov**, **A.**, Howse, J., Stapleton, G. and Delaney, A. (2018) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (long paper).
- 3. **Baimagambetov**, **A.** (2018) Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Graduate Symposium report).